<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spencer Lyon</title>
    <link>http://spencerlyon.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Spencer Lyon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <managingEditor>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2015-2017 Spencer Lyon.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 12:06:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://spencerlyon.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://spencerlyon.com/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2017 12:06:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</author>
      <guid>http://spencerlyon.com/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Data Bootcamp Working with Dave Backus and Chase Coleman, I helped create the Data Bootcamp course at NYU stern and taught it for multiple semesters. The class is aimed at advanced undergraduates or MBA students who have no programming experience. The goal is to teach them the basics of Python and its data-handling tools and prepare them to gather/clean/explore/visualize real-world data. See our sales pitch for more info.
As of right now (2017-06-08) all materials are online and available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://spencerlyon.com/presentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 12:06:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</author>
      <guid>http://spencerlyon.com/presentations/</guid>
      <description>Presentations NOTE: This is an incomplete list and will be updated when I find the time. Some of the ones that aren&amp;rsquo;t itemized can be found in this GitHub repository.
Economics  Economic modeling in Julia with an application to the FRBNY DSGE model @ CEF 2017 &amp;ndash; repository &amp;ndash; with Chase Coleman, Abhi Gupta, Pearl Li, and Erica Moszkowski The Dolo modeling framework @ CEF 2017 &amp;ndash; slides &amp;ndash; with James Graham, Pablo Winant, and Anastasia Zhutova  Programming  Methods, Models, and Moments: Julian Economics with QuantEcon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://spencerlyon.com/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 15:48:14 -0700</pubDate>
      <author>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</author>
      <guid>http://spencerlyon.com/publications/</guid>
      <description>Research Papers Pareto Weights as Wedges in Two-Country Models  with Dave Backus, Chase Coleman, Axelle Ferriere (JEDC 2016)   In models with recursive preferences, endogenous variation in Pareto weights would be interpreted as wedges from the perspective of a frictionless model with additive preferences. We describe the behavior of the (relative) Pareto weight in a two-country world and explore its interaction with consumption and the real exchange rate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://spencerlyon.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2015 13:57:03 -0500</pubDate>
      <author>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</author>
      <guid>http://spencerlyon.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I live in NYC with my beautiful wife and three awesome kids.
I&amp;rsquo;m a PhD student in the Economics department in the New York University Stern School of Business.
I am a member of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints (also known as Mormon).
In addition to family, school, and religion; I am also interested in sports, food, and programming. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly active in the Julia community and also (occasionally) contribute to the SciPy/PyData ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canonical Probability distributions in Python</title>
      <link>http://spencerlyon.com/2015/01/07/canonical-probability-distributions-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>spencer.lyon@stern.nyu.edu (Spencer Lyon)</author>
      <guid>http://spencerlyon.com/2015/01/07/canonical-probability-distributions-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Distributions.jl I often need to use probability distributions in my work and research. Julia has an excellent package, Distributions.jl, for representing many common probability distributions. The three main features I like from this package are
 Excellent documentation where they clearly specify the methods available to each probability distribution as well as the parameterization used to define the pdf Canonical parameterizations for all distributions. By canonical I mean the form of the pdf you would find on the Wikipedia page for a particular distribution or open up a standard reference like Bayesian Data Analysis (Gelman, 2013) A consistent interface to all distributions of the same type.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>